Guide to the H. Lee Waters Film Collection, 1936-2005 (bulk 1936-1942)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
H. Lee Waters Film collection 1936-2005 (bulk 1936-1942)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Waters, H. Lee.
47.25 linear feet Extent: 430 Items
Born in Caroleen, North Carolina in 1902, studio photographer Herbert Lee Waters supplemented his income from 1936 to 1942 by traveling across North Carolina and parts of Virginia, Tennessee, and South Carolina to film the people of small communities. He collaborated with local movie theaters to screen his films, which he called Movies of Local People. As a filmmaker, Waters produced 252 films across 118 communities. The H. Lee Waters Film Collection dates from 1936 to 2005 and primarily comprises 16 mm black and white reversal original motion picture films created by Waters during the filming of the Movies of Local People series. The collection, arranged alphabetically by town name, also includes various preservation elements created from the original footage: 16 mm internegatives; 16 mm screening prints; 3/4 inch Umatic, Betacam SP, and Digital Betacam preservation tape masters; and VHS and DVD use copies of Waters' works. The collection contains a small number of papers and physical objects related to Waters' film making, including: a photocopy of two log books (encompassed in one volume) maintained by Waters to record financial and business information during the filming of Movies of Local People; photocopied and original advertisements for screenings of Waters' films; photocopies of Waters' notes, receipts, and correspondence concerning film sales; related ephemera; and a copy of a 2005 master's thesis written on the films of H. Lee Waters.
watershlee
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. However, original audiovisual materials are CLOSED to patron use. Use copies are available in the collection.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The H. Lee Waters Film Collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a series of gifts and purchases beginning in 1988.
Biographical Note
Born August 23, 1902, Herbert Lee Waters spent the majority of his life in Lexington, North Carolina operating a photography studio. Waters supplemented his income from 1936-1942 by traveling across North Carolina and parts of Virginia, Tennessee, and South Carolina to film the people of small communities. He collaborated with local movie theaters to screen his films, which he called Movies of Local People and billed with the phrase "See yourself in the movies!" As a filmmaker, Waters produced 252 films across 118 communities. In 1942, Waters returned to Lexington and continued operating his photographic studio until his death in 1997. The Library of Congress listed Waters' Kannapolis film on the National Film Registry in 2004.
Collection Overview
The H. Lee Waters Film Collection dates from 1936 to 2005 and comprises primarily 16 mm black and white reversal original motion picture films created by Waters between 1936 and 1942 as he traveled across North Carolina, South Carolina, and Virginia filming the residents of small towns. Waters aimed to film as many residents in each community as possible, often setting up his camera at the main intersection in town to capture community members walking downtown. Waters also typically filmed school children entering or leaving school and workers arriving to or departing from mills, plants, and factories. Waters often included trick shots to engage his audience, such as trains moving backwards or children jumping in reverse. Although the films are dominated by shots of crowds and individual faces, Waters also captured a wide variety of activities, like school recitals, sports, mechanics at work, and manufacturing processes in factories.
The collection, arranged alphabetically by town name, includes various preservation elements created from the original footage: 16 mm internegatives; 16 mm screening prints; 3/4 inch Umatic, Betacam SP, and Digital Betacam preservation tape masters; and VHS and DVD use copies of Waters' works. The majority of films represented in the collection are silent, black and white, and were filmed in North Carolina. The collection includes a small number of color films and one film with sound. Reels containing mixed black and white and color footage were separated into two reels based on picture characteristic during the preservation process.
The collection also contains a small number of papers and physical objects related to Waters, including: photocopied and original advertisements for screenings of Waters' films; photocopies of Waters' notes, receipts, and correspondence concerning film sales; related ephemera; VHS copies of a news report and a film on Waters; and a copy of the master's thesis written on the films of H. Lee Waters by University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill student Martin Johnson in 2005. In addition, the collection contains a photocopy of two log books (encompassed in one volume) maintained by Waters between the years of 1936 and 1942 to document his earnings from the Movies of Local People films. The logs provide information about film screenings in the towns that he visited, including the dates of the screenings, the theaters where the films played, admission prices, the number of tickets sold, and advertising revenues. Printed copies of shot lists, created by a student intern, are included in the collection. The detailed description of the collection indicates if shot lists are available for a particular film.
Topical Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
16mm; Black-and-white film; Children -- North Carolina; Cinematographers -- North Carolina; Cities and towns -- North Carolina; Color film (film).; Depressions -- 1929 -- North Carolina; Depressions -- 1929 -- South Carolina.; Depressions -- 1929 -- Virginia.; Documentary films -- North Carolina; Factories -- North Carolina.; North Carolina -- History -- 1900-1944; North Carolina -- History -- 20th century.; Mills and mill-work -- North Carolina; Motion pictures -- North Carolina; Motion pictures -- Production and direction -- North Carolina; Motion picture film collections; North Carolina -- In motion pictures; North Carolina -- Rural conditions; Photographers -- North Carolina; Reversal film; Schools -- North Carolina; South Carolina -- In motion pictures; Virginia -- In motion pictures; Waters, H. Lee
Geographical Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Albemarle (N.C.); Asheboro (N.C.); Avondale (N.C.); Benson (N.C.); Caroleen (N.C.); Chapel Hill (N.C.); Chester (S.C.); Clayton (N.C.); Cliffside (N.C.); Cramerton (N.C.); Damascus (Va.); Dante (Va.); Danville (Va.); Denton (N.C.); Erwin (N.C.); Forest City (N.C.); Fuquay-Varina (N.C.); Gastonia (N.C.); Granite Falls (N.C.); Greensboro (N.C.); Henderson (N.C.); Henrietta (N.C.); Jackson (N.C.); Kannapolis (N.C.); Lebanon (Va.); Lenoir (N.C.); Lexington (N.C.); Liberty (N.C.); Lillington (N.C.); Madison (N.C.); Mayodan (N.C.); Martinsville (Va.); Mebane (N.C.); Mooresville (N.C.); Mt. Airy (N.C.); North Wilkesboro (N.C.); Oxford (N.C.); Pilot Mountain (N.C.); Raeford (N.C.); Reidsville (N.C.); Roxboro (N.C.); Rutherfordton (N.C.); Salisbury (N.C.); Scotland Neck (N.C.); Selma (N.C.); Siler City (N.C.); Smithfield (N.C.); Spindale (N.C.); Statesville (N.C.); Swannanoa (N.C.); Taylorsville (N.C.); Thomasville (N.C.); Troy (N.C.); Whitmire (S.C.); Winnsboro (S.C.); Wytheville (Va.)
Contents of Collection
- Albemarle (N.C.), circa 1936
  Screening Date: 1936 August 20-21.
  Screening Theatre: Stanley Theatre.
  Use Copies: DVD and VHS use copies available.
- Asheboro (N.C.), circa 1938-1939
  Screening Date: 1939 February 06-07.
  Screening Theatre: Capitol Theatre.
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, col., reel 1 of 2, (600 ft.) (Box 1)
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 2 of 2, (400 ft.) (Box 1)
- Asheboro (N.C.), 1939 November 23
  Screening Date: 1940 February 05-06.
  Use Copies: DVD use copy available.
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., col., reel 1 of 1, (100 ft.) (Box 1)
  - Internegative, 16 mm, si., col., reel 1 of 1 (Box 12)
  - Screening print, 16 mm, si., col., reel 1 of 1 (Box 20)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 4:00) (Box 27)
- Asheboro (N.C.), 1940 March 01
  Screened on one of the following dates: 1941 January 13-14; 1941 December 01-02.
  Use Copies: DVD and VHS use copies available. Shot list available, see box 34.
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1, (400 ft.) (Box 1)
  - Internegative, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1 (Box 12)
  - Screening print, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1 (Box 20)
  - Preservation tape master, Betacam SP, (TRT: 76:00, including footage of Cherryville (N.C.), Granite Falls (N.C.), and Lenoir(N.C.)) (Box 27)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 76:00, including footage of Cherryville (N.C.), Granite Falls (N.C.), and Lenoir (N.C.)) (Box 27)
- Asheboro (N.C.), 1940
  Screened on one of the following dates: 1940 February 05-06; 1941 January 13-14.
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, sd., col., reel 1 of 1, (1000 ft.) (Box 1)
  - Internegative, 16 mm, si., col., reel 1 of 1 (Box 12)
  - Optical sound negative, 16 mm, sd., reel 1 of 1 (Box 12)
  - Optical sound negative, 16 mm, sd., reel 1 of 1, duplicate (Box 12)
  - Composite screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., reel 1 of 1 (Box 20)
  - Composite work print, 16 mm, sd., col., reel 1 of 1 (Box 20)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 28:00) (Box 27)
- Asheboro (N.C.), circa 1940-1941
  Screening Date: 1941 January 13.
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., col., reel 1 of 1, (900 ft.) (Box 1)
- Asheboro (N.C.), circa 1938-1941
  Screened on one of the following dates: 1938 January 31-February 01; 1939 February 06-07; 1940 February 05-06; 1941 January 13-14; 1941 December 01-02.
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1, (150 ft.) (Box 1)
  - Internegative, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1 (Box 12)
  - Screening print, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1 (Box 20)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 6:30) (Box 27)
- Benson (N.C.), circa 1937
  Screening Date: 1937 March 16.
  Screening Theatre: Benson Theatre.
  Use Copies: VHS use copy available. Shot list available, see box 34.
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1, (600 ft.) (Box 1)
  - Internegative, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1 (Box 12)
  - Preservation tape master, 3/4 inch Umatic, (TRT: 19:24) (Box 27)
  - Preservation tape master, 3/4 inch Umatic, duplicate (Box 27)
  - Preservation tape master, Betacam SP, (TRT: 19:24) (Box 27)
- Caroleen (N.C.), Avondale (N.C.), and Henrietta (N.C.), 1940
  Screening Date: 1940 October 02-03.
  Screening Theatre: Cliffside Theatre.
  Originally part of the 1940 Cliffside reel.
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1, (200 ft.) (Box 2)
  - Internegative, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1 (Box 12)
  - Screening print, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1 (Box 20)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 7:40) (Box 27)
- Chapel Hill (N.C.), 1939
  Screening Date: 1939 October 06-07.
  Screening Theatre: Hollywood Theatre.
  Use Copies: VHS use copy available, reel 1 of 2. Shot list available, reel 1 of 2, see box 33.
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 2, (300 ft.) (Box 2)
  - Internegative, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 2 (Box 12)
  - Preservation tape master, Betacam SP, reel 1 of 2, (TRT: 9:50) (Box 27)
  - Preservation tape master, Betacam SP, duplicate, reel 1 of 2 (Box 27)
  - Preservation tape master, Betacam SP, reel 2 of 2, (TRT: 20:12) (Box 27)
- Clayton (N.C.), circa 1936-1937
  Screening Date: 1937 February.
  Screening Theatre: Wades Theatre.
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1, (300 ft.) (Box 2)
  - Internegative, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1 (Box 12)
  - Preservation tape master, 3/4 inch Umatic, (TRT: 13:00) (Box 27)
  - Preservation tape master, Betacam SP, (TRT: 13:00) (Box 27)
- Cliffside (N.C.), 1937
  Screening Date: 1937 August 04.
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1, (500 ft.) (Box 2)
  - Internegative, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1 (Box 13)
  - Screening print, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1 (Box 21)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 39:30, including footage of Cliffside (N.C.), 1940) (Box 27)
- Cliffside (N.C.), 1940
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, col., reel 1 of 1, (600 ft.) (Box 2)
  - Internegative, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1 (Box 13)
  - Screening print, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1 (Box 21)
  - Screening print, 16 mm, si., col., reel 1 of 1 (Box 21)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 39:30, including footage of Cliffside (N.C.), 1937) (Box 27)
- Cramerton (N.C.), circa 1938-1939
  Screened on one of the following dates: 1938 October 10-11; 1939 April 24-25.
  Screening Theatre: Midway Theatre.
  Original footage was 16 mm, si., b&w, (1200 ft.)
  Use Copies: VHS use copy available, reels 1 and 3. DVD and VHS use copies available, reel 2.
  - Preservation tape master, 3/4 inch Umatic, reel 2 of 3, (TRT: 11:35) (Box 27)
- Damascus (Va.), 1940
  Screening Date: 1940 December 04-05.
  Screening Theatre: State Theatre.
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1, (600 ft). (Reel 4)
  - Internegative, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1 (Box 13)
  - Screening print, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1 (Box 21)
  - Preservation tape master, 3/4 inch Umatic, (TRT: 23:23) (Box 28)
  - Preservation tape master, Betacam SP, (TRT: 23:23) (Box 28)
- Dante (Va.), 1940
  Screening Date: 1940 December 13-14.
  Screening Theatre: Dante Theatre.
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 2, (300 ft.) (Box 2)
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 2 of 2, (400 ft.) (Box 2)
  - Internegative, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 2 (Box 13)
  - Internegative, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 2 of 2 (Box 13)
  - Screening print, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 2 (Box 21)
  - Screening print, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 2 of 2 (Box 21)
  - Preservation tape master, 3/4 inch Umatic, reel 1 of 2, (TRT: 12:30) (Box 28)
  - Preservation tape master, 3/4 inch Umatic, reel 2 of 2, (TRT: 15:20) (Box 28)
  - Preservation tape master, Betacam SP, (TRT: 28:07, including footage from reels 1 and 2) (Box 28)
- Danville (Va.), circa 1939
  Screening Date: 1939 March 06-07.
  Screening Theatre: Virginia Theatre.
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, col., reel 1 of 1, (800 ft.) (Box 3)
- Denton (N.C.), circa 1939-1941
  Screened on one of the following dates: 1939 December 04-05; 1941 February 03-04.
  Screening Theatre: Anchor Theatre.
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 3, (1000 ft.) (Box 3)
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 2 of 3, (300 ft.) (Box 3)
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 3 of 3, (300 ft.) (Box 3)
  - Preservation tape master, 3/4 inch Umatic, reel 1 of 3, (TRT: 37:15) (Box 28)
  - Preservation tape master, 3/4 inch Umatic, reel 2 of 3, (TRT: 11:47) (Box 28)
  - Preservation tape master, 3/4 inch Umatic, reel 3 of 3, (TRT: 11:04) (Box 28)
- Erwin (N.C.), circa 1937-1939
  Screened on one of the following dates: 1937 February; 1939 May 25-26.
  Screening Theatre: Peerless Theatre.
  - Master positive, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 2, (1200 ft.) (Box 3)
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 2 of 2, (1200 ft.) (Reel 11)
  - Internegative, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 2 (Box 13)
  - Screening print, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 2 (Box 21)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, reel 1 of 2, (TRT: 44:23) (Box 28)
- Forest City (N.C.), 1937
  Screening Date: 1937 June 17-18.
  Screening Theatre: Romina Theatre.
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1, (500 ft.) (Box 3)
- Fuquay-Varina (N.C.), circa 1937
  Screening Date: 1937 March 11-12.
  Screening Theatre: Wade's Theatre.
  - Master positive, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1, (500 ft.) (Box 3)
  - Internegative, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1 (Box 13)
  - Screening print, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1 (Box 21)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 16:58) (Box 28)
- Gastonia (N.C.), 1937
  Screening Date: 1937 July 01-02.
  Screening Theatre: Carolina Theatre.
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1, (100 ft.) (Box 3)
- Gastonia (N.C.), 1939
  Screening Date: 1939 May 01-02.
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 2 of 3, (400 ft.) (Box 4)
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 3 of 3, (400 ft.) (Box 4)
  - Preservation tape master, 3/4 inch Umatic, (TRT: circa 39:00, including footage from reels 1-3) (Box 28)
- Gastonia (N.C.), 1940
  Screening Date: 1940 September 23-24.
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 2, (350 ft.) (Box 4)
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 2 of 2, (400 ft.) (Box 4)
  - Preservation tape master, 3/4 inch Umatic, (TRT: circa 25:00, including footage from reels 1 and 2) (Box 28)
- Gastonia (N.C.), circa 1942
  Screening Date: 1942 April 20-21.
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., col., reel 1 of 1, (800 ft.) (Box 4)
- Granite Falls (N.C.), circa 1938
  Screening Date: 1938 November 28-29.
  Screening Theatre: Lyric Theatre.
  Use Copies: DVD use copies available. VHS use copy available, reels 1, 3, and 4. Shot list available, reels 1-2 and 4, see box 33.
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 4, (400 ft.) (Box 4)
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, col., reel 2 of 4, (300 ft.) (Box 4)
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 3 of 4, (400 ft.) (Box 4)
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 4 of 4, (400 ft.) (Box 2)
  - Internegative, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 2 of 4 (Box 14)
  - Color separation negative, 16 mm, si., col., reel 2 of 4 (Box 14)
  - Screening print, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 4 (Box 22)
  - Screening print, 16 mm, si., b&w, col., reel 2 of 4 (Box 22)
  - Screening print, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 3 of 4 (Box 22)
  - Screening print, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 4 of 4 (Box 20)
  - Preservation tape master, Betacam SP, reels 1, 3, and 4 of 4, (TRT: 76:00, including footage of Asheboro (N.C.) and Lenoir (N.C.)) (Box 27)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, reels 1, 3, and 4 of 4, (TRT: 76:00, including footage of Asheboro (N.C.) and Lenoir (N.C.)) (Box 27)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, reel 2 of 3, (TRT: 10:00) (Box 28)
- Granite Falls (N.C.), 1941, circa 1942
  Screening Dates: 1941 November 10-11; 1942 June 22-23.
  Screening Theatre: Main Theatre.
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, col., reel 1 of 1, (1000 ft.) (Box 4)
  - Internegative, 16 mm, si., col., reel 1 of 1 (Box 14)
  - Screening print, 16 mm, si., b&w, col., reel 1 of 1 (Box 22)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 42:00) (Box 28)
- Greensboro (N.C.), circa 1939
  Screening Date: 1939 July 17-18.
  Screening Theatre: Center Theatre.
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1, (750 ft.) (Box 5)
  - Internegative, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1 (Box 14)
  - Preservation tape master, Betacam SP, (TRT: 21:24) (Box 29)
- Henderson (N.C.), circa 1938
  Screening Date: 1938 September 15-16.
  Screening Theatre: Stevenson Theatre.
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1, (900 ft.) (Reel 9)
  - Internegative, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1 (Box 14)
  - Preservation tape master, 3/4 inch Umatic, (TRT: 34:00) (Box 27)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 34:00) (Box 29)
- Jackson (N.C.), 1939
  Screening Date: 1939 September 14-15.
  Screening Theatre: Jackson Theatre.
  Includes footage of Seaboard, Conway, Lasker, and Weldon.
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1, (600 ft.) (Box 5)
  - Screening print, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1 (Box 22)
  - Preservation tape master, Betacam SP, (TRT: 22:20) (Box 29)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 22:20) (Box 29)
- Kannapolis (N.C.), 1941
  Screened on one of the following dates: 1941 February 06-07; 1941 October 01-02.
  Screening Theatre: Dixie Theatre and Palace Theatre (1941 February); Swanee Theatre (1941 October).
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., col., reel 1 of 3, (900 ft.) (Box 5)
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 2 of 3, (1400 ft.) (Reel 8)
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 3 of 3, (1000 ft.) (Box 5)
  - Internegative, 16 mm, si., col., reel 1 of 3 (Box 14)
  - Internegative, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 2 of 3 (Box 14)
  - Internegative, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 3 of 3 (Box 14)
  - Screening print, 16 mm, si., col., reel 1 of 3 (Box 22)
  - Screening print, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 2 of 3 (Box 22)
  - Screening print, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 3 of 3 (Box 22)
  - Preservation tape master, Betacam SP, reel 3 of 3, (TRT: 47:00) (Box 29)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, reel 1 of 3, (TRT: 35:00) (Box 29)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, reel 2 of 3, (TRT: 55:00) (Box 29)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, reel 3 of 3, (TRT: 47:00) (Box 29)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, reel 3 of 3, duplicate (Box 29)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, reel 3 of 3, duplicate (Box 29)
- Kannapolis (N.C.), circa 1936-1941
  Screened on one of the following dates: 1936 July 30-31; 1936 September 09; 1938 May 12-13; 1940 August 29-30; 1941 February 06-07; 1941 October 01-02.
  Screened at one of the following theatres: Y.M.C.A. Theatre (1936); Colonial Theatre (1938); Dixie Theatre and Palace Theatre (1940, 1941 February);Swanee Theatre (1941 October).
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1, (500 ft.) (Box 5)
- Lebanon (Va.), 1940
  Screening Date: 1940 October 14-15.
  Screening Theatre: Russell Theatre.
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1, (200 ft.) (Box 5)
  - Internegative, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1 (Box 15)
  - Screening print, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1 (Box 23)
  - Preservation tape master, Betacam SP, (TRT: 7:18) (Box 28)
  - Preservation tape master, 3/4 inch Umatic, (TRT: 7:18) (Box 29)
- Lenoir (N.C.), circa 1937
  Screening Date: 1937 April 28-30.
  Screening Theatre: Avon Theatre.
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1, (600 ft.) (Box 5)
  - Screening print, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1 (Box 23)
  - Preservation tape master, Betacam SP, (TRT: 76:00, including footage of Asheboro (N.C.), Cherryville (N.C.), and Granite Falls (N.C.)) (Box 27)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 76:00, including footage of Asheboro (N.C.), Cherryville (N.C.), and Granite Falls (N.C.)) (Box 27)
- Lexington (N.C.), circa 1935-1953
  Screening Date: 1938 May 05-06.
  Screening Theatre: Lexington High School.
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1, (700 ft.) (Box 6)
  - Internegative, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1 (Box 15)
  - Screening print, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1 (Box 23)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 59:40, including footage of Lexington (N.C.), circa 1937-1945) (Box 29)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, duplicate (Box 29)
- Lexington (N.C.), circa 1937-1945
  - Reversal original, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1, (800 ft.) (Box 6)
  - Internegative, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1 (Box 15)
  - Screening print, 16 mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1 (Box 23)